Guide to Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) Assorted Maps and Atlases, 1830-1990 AIS.Maps
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Atlases, 1788-1990; VIII.
  - Sanborn Maps, 1.
    - Sewickley, Pa., 1944
    - Rochester, Pa., 1925
    - Pittsburg, Volume 1, 1923 (Shelf 1/1/2)
    - Pittsburg, Volume 2, 1923
    - Pittsburg, Volume 3, 1923
    - Pittsburg, Volume 4, 1919
    - Pittsburg, Volume 5, 1920
    - Pittsburg, Volume 6, 1920
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 1, 1936 (Shelf 1/1/3)
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 2, 1938
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 3, 1932
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 3, 1938
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 4, 1931
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 4, 1935 (Shelf 1/1/4)
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 5, 1931
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 6, 1931
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 7, 1931
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 8, 1931
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 9, 1931
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 10, 1935 (Shelf 1/1/5)
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 11, 1930
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 12, 1931
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 13, 1931
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 14, 1931
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 15, 1931
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 16, 1931 (Shelf 1/1/6)
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 17, 1931
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 18, 1931
    - Pittsburgh, Index, Volume 1-18, 1928
    - Allegheny City, Volume 1, 1924
    - Allegheny City, Volume 2, 1924
  - Hopkins Plat Books and Atlases, 2.
    Please note that the Historic Pittsburgh website provides online access to all 47 volumes of maps published by the G. M. Hopkins Company for Pittsburgh. The Archives Service Center holds 40 of the 47 volumes. These plat maps cover the greater Pittsburgh area through the years 1872 to 1940.
    - Allegheny City, Volume 1 (Wards 1-8, 12-13), 1901 (Shelf 1/1/7)
      North Shore, Manchester, Chateau, Allegheny Center, East Allegheny, Troy Hill, California Kirkbride
    - Allegheny City, Volume 2 (Wards 9-11, 14-15), 1902
      Fineview, Brighton Heights, Marshall-Shadeland, Summer Hill, Perry North, Northview Heights, Spring Hill, Perry South
    - Allegheny City, Volume 1 (Wards 1-8, 12-13), 1907
      North Shore, Manchester, Chateau, Allegheny Center, East Allegheny, Troy Hill, Washington's Landing
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 1 (Wards 1-11), 1889 (Shelf 1/2/3)
      Downtown, Strip District, Hill District
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 2 (Wards 12-14), 1889
      Hill District, Oakland, Polish Hill, Strip District
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 3 (Wards 15, 17-19, 21), 1890
      Lawrenceville, Stanton Heights, Morningside, Garfield, Highland Park, East Liberty, Lincoln-Lemington-Belmar, Larimer, Homewood
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 4 (Wards 16, 20, 22-23), 1890
      Shadyside, Squirrel Hill, Point Breeze, Greenfield, Hazelwood, Glen Hazel
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 1 (East End, Wards 13-14, 22-23), 1898
      Bluff, Oakland, Crawford Roberts, Hill District, Greenfield, Hazelwood, Squirrel Hill, Point Breeze, Swisshelm Park
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 2 (East End, Wards 18-21), 1899
      Shadyside, Bloomfield, Friendship, Lawrenceville, Garfield, Highland Park, East Liberty, Homewood, Lincoln-Lemington-Belmar, Larimer
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 3 (Wards 1-12, 15-17), 1900
      Downtown, Strip District, Hill District, Polish Hill, Lawrenceville, Bloomfield
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 3 Supplement (Wards 1-9), 1903
      Downtown
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 4 (Wards 24-36), 1901
      Duquesne Heights, Mount Washington, Beltzhoover, South Side, Allentown
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 1 (Wards 13-14, 22-23), 1904
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 2 (Wards 18-21, 27), 1904
      Shadyside, Bloomfield, Friendship, Lawrenceville, Stanton Heights, Morningside, Garfield, Lincoln-Lemington-Belmar, Larimer, Homewood, East Hills
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 3 (Wards 6-12, 15-17), 1906
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 3 (Wards 8, 10-13), 1911 (Shelf 1/2/4)
      Bloomfield, Friendship, Lawrenceville, Stanton Heights, Morningside, Garfield, Highland Park, East Liberty, Lincoln-Lemington-Belmar, Larimer, Homewood, East Hills
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 4 (Wards 7, 14-5), 1911
      Shadyside, Squirrel Hill, Point Breeze, Regent Square, Swisshelm Park, Greenfield, Glen Hazel, Hazelwood
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 2 (Wards 1-6, 9), 1914
      Downtown, Bluff, Strip District, Crawford Roberts, Oakland, Terrace Village, Middle Hill, Bedford Dwellings, Upper Hill, Polish Hill, Lawrenceville
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 7 (Southern Vicinity), 1915
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 8 (Eastern Vicinity), 1915
      Wilkinsburg, Penn Hills, Brushton, Braddock, Rankin, Turtle Creek, East Pittsburgh, Forest Hills, Edgewood, Swissvale, Wilmerding, Pitcairn, North Versailles, Wall, Monroeville, Trafford, Oakmont, Verona
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 6 (Southern Vicinity, East Half), 1916
      South Side, Knoxville, Mt. Oliver, St. Clair, Carrick, Brentwood, Dormont, Mt. Lebanon, Arlington, Arlington Heights, Hays
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 7 (Southern Vicinity, West Half), 1917
      South Shore, Beltzhoover, Bon Air, Beechview, Brookline, Overbrook, Banksville, Castle Shannon, Scott Township, Heidleberg, Glendale, Carnegie, Rosslyn Farms, Greentree, Chartiers, Crafton, Ingram, Westwood, Duquesne Heights, McKees Rocks, Coraopolis, Bridgeville
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 1 (Wards 1-6, 9), 1923 (Shelf 1/2/5)
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 2 (Wards 7, 14-15), 1923
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 3 (Wards 8, 10-13), 1925
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 4 (Wards 22-26), 1925
      East Allegheny, Troy Hill, Spring Garden, Summer Hill, Perry North, Northview Heights, Spring Hill, Perry South, North Shore, Allegheny Center, Manchester West, Fineview, California Kirkbride
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 5 (Wards 21-22, 25, 27), 1925
      Manchester, Chateau, Brighton Heights, Marshall-Shadeland, North Shore, Allegheny Center, Manchester West, Fineview
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 10 (Wards 1-3), 1929
      Downtown, Bluff, Strip District, Crawford Roberts
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 9 (Wards 19, 32), 1934
      Beechview, Dormont, Brookline, Overbrook, Mt. Lebanon, Castle Shannon, Baldwin Township, Bethel Township, Snowden Township
    - Pittsburgh, Volume 2 (Wards 7, 14-15), 1939
    - Pittsburgh, Northern Vicinity, 1897 (Shelf 1/2/6)
      Sewickley, Osborne, Glenfield, Emsworth, Ben Avon, Avalon, Bellevue, West View, Brookville, Spring Garden, Millvale, Etna, Sharpsburg, Aspinwall, Fox Chapel, Verona, Oakmont
    - Pittsburgh, Northern Vicinity, 1906
      Leetsdale, Edgeworth, Sewickley, Osborne, Glenfield, Emsworth, Ben Avon, Avalon, Bellevue, West View, Ross Township, McCandless Township, Kilbuck Township, Aleppo Township, Sewickley Heights, Sharpsburg, Etna, Aspinwall, Millvale, Spring Garden, Glenshaw, Fox Chapel, Blawnox
    - Pittsburgh, Southeastern Vicinity, 1900
      McKeesport, Homestead, Mifflin, Duquesne, Port Vue, Versailles, Elizabeth, Forward, Dravosburg, Glassport
    - Pittsburgh, Southern Vicinity, 1896
      Baldwin, Castle Shannon, Greentree, McKees Rocks, Sheraden, Esplen, Elliot, Beechview, Bon Air, Crafton, Chartiers, Banksville, Beltzhoover, Lower St. Clair, Knoxville, Carrick, Overbrook, Hays, Whitehall
    - Pittsburgh, Southern Vicinity, 1905
    - Pittsburgh, Eastern Vicinity, 1895
      Wilkinsburg, Penn Hills, Brushton, Braddock, Rankin, Turtle Creek, East Pittsburgh, Forest Hills, Edgewood, Swissvale, Wilmerding, Pitcairn, North Versailles, Wall, Monroeville
    - Pittsburgh, Eastern Vicinity, 1903
    - Pittsburgh, Allegheny City & Adjoining Boroughs, 1872 (Shelf 1/2/7)
      City of Pittsburgh, North Side, South Side
    - Pittsburgh & Allegheny City, 1882
    - Pittsburgh & Allegheny City, 1886
      Greater Pittsburgh area
    - Pittsburgh, 1910
      City of Pittsburgh
  - City of Pittsburgh, 3.
    - Ideal Atlas of Pittsburgh and Vicinity, 1955 (Shelf 1/1/7)
    - Ideal Atlas of Pittsburgh and Vicinity, 1968
    - Atlas of Pittsburgh, 1911 (Shelf 1/3/2)
    - Pittsburgh Figured Out: The Pittsburgh Map Project, 1990
    - Pittsburgh Dept. of City Planning Topographic Sheets, City of Pittsburgh, 1960
    - "Z" atlas & map of Pittsburgh, Pa., and Mount Oliver, Pa., 1952; 2 items
    - Lytle & Foran Map of Pittsburgh, 1907
  - Pennsylvania Counties, 4.
    - Hopkins Atlas of Allegheny County, 1876 (Shelf 1/1/7)
    - Warrantee Atlas of Allegheny County, 1914
    - Pomery, Whitman Atlas of Armstrong County, 1876
    - Hopkins Atlas of Butler County, 1874
    - Caldwell Atlas of Clarion County, 1877
    - Hopkins Atlas of Fayette County, 1872
    - Beers Atlas of Indiana County, 1871
    - Everts & Stewart Atlas of Lancaster County, 1875
    - Hopkins Atlas of Montgomery County, 1871
    - J. L. Smith Atlas of Montgomery County, 1893
    - Beers Atlas of Union & Snyder Counties, 1869
    - Beers Atlas of Wayne County, 1872
  - Pennsylvania and Other States, 5.
    - Sanborn Atlas of Whiskey Warehouses in Pennsylvania, West Virginia, Maryland, New Jersey and New York, 1894 (Shelf 1/3/2)
    - Columbia Magazine's New and Accurate Map of the State of Pennsylvania, 1788
    - Pittsburgh & Lake Erie Railroad's Economic Atlas of the Pittsburgh-Youngstown Economic Area, 1960